const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"During translation, the initiation codon of mRNA attaches to the ribosome at which site?","answers":[{"option":"A site of 50S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"E site of 50S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"P site of 30S subunit","bool":true},{"option":"E site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"A site of 30S subunit","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"From which of the following does the external urethral meatus develop?","answers":[{"option":"Anal folds","bool":false},{"option":"Scrotal swellings","bool":false},{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Phallus","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral folds","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A woman presents to the clinic with the complaint of cessation of the menstrual cycle for the last 3 months. Previously she had regular menstruation occurring every 30th day and continued for 4 days. On what day of the cycle this woman is most likely to ovulate?","answers":[{"option":"14th day","bool":false},{"option":"7th day","bool":false},{"option":"30th day","bool":false},{"option":"16th day","bool":true},{"option":"28th day","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which enzyme is responsible for releasing DNA supercoils?","answers":[{"option":"DNA ligase","bool":false},{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Single strand DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which type of epithelial transition is seen between the vagina and cervix?","answers":[{"option":"Simple squamous to stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous to simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous to simple columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified squamous to stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple columnar to simple squamous epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following structures surrounds part of the urethra?","answers":[{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate","bool":true},{"option":"Bulbourethral gland","bool":false},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which part of the levator ani muscle plays a major role in maintaining fecal continence?","answers":[{"option":"Puboannalis","bool":false},{"option":"Pubococcygeus","bool":false},{"option":"Iliococcygeus","bool":false},{"option":"Puborectalis","bool":true},{"option":"Puboperinealis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"The placenta is composed of two parts: 5/6th fetal and 1/6th maternal. The maternal placenta is formed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Decidua parietalis","bool":false},{"option":"Decidua basalis and chorion frondosum","bool":false},{"option":"Chorion laeve","bool":false},{"option":"Decidua basalis","bool":true},{"option":"Decidua capsularis","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following is not included in the boundaries of perineum?","answers":[{"option":"Pubic symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Ischiopubic rami","bool":false},{"option":"Imaginary line joining two ischial tuberosities","bool":true},{"option":"Coccyx","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial tuberosity","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following glands are located in the deep perineal pouch of males?","answers":[{"option":"Bulbourethral glands","bool":true},{"option":"Prostatic glands","bool":false},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Modified sweat glands","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral glands","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following does not form the placental barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Capillary endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Amniotic membrane","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following sites in the male reproductive system is associated with storage and maturation of sperms?","answers":[{"option":"Epididymis","bool":true},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the normal description of the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Retroflexed and anteverted","bool":false},{"option":"Anteflexed and retroverted","bool":false},{"option":"Anteflexed and anteverted","bool":true},{"option":"Anteverted and retroextended","bool":false},{"option":"Retroflexed and retroverted","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the blood supply of the prostate gland?","answers":[{"option":"Branch of external iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle rectal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Superior vesical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Artery of vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"The urogenital triangle is not bounded by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ischial tuberosity","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial rami","bool":false},{"option":"Coccyx","bool":true},{"option":"Pubic rami","bool":false},{"option":"Pubic symphysis","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following landmarks is not a part of linea terminalis?","answers":[{"option":"Medial border of ilium","bool":true},{"option":"Pectineal line of pubis","bool":false},{"option":"Sacral promontory","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate line","bool":false},{"option":"Pubic crest","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"What is the primary function of Leydig cells in the testes?","answers":[{"option":"Sustentacular cell production","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Sperm production","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone production","bool":true},{"option":"Hormonal regulation","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following structures forms labia minora of the female external genitalia?","answers":[{"option":"Phallus","bool":false},{"option":"Anal fold","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral fold","bool":true},{"option":"Genital swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Genital tubercle","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which cells surround and nurture developing oocytes within the ovary?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Theca externa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":true},{"option":"Luteal cells","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following properties of the prostatic capsule differentiates it from other glandular capsules?","answers":[{"option":"Collagenous fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Glands","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following correctly lists the protective coverings of the testes from outermost to innermost?","answers":[{"option":"Parietal layer of tunica vaginalis, visceral layer of tunica vaginalis, tunica albuginea, tunica vasculosa","bool":true},{"option":"Tunica albuginea, tunica vasculosa, parietal layer of tunica vaginalis, visceral layer of tunica vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Tunica vasculosa, parietal layer of tunica vaginalis, visceral layer of tunica vaginalis, tunica albuginea","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral layer of tunica vaginalis, parietal layer of tunica vaginalis, tunica albuginea, tunica vasculosa","bool":false},{"option":"Tunica vasculosa, tunica albuginea, parietal layer of tunica vaginalis, visceral layer of tunica vaginalis","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following ligaments anchors the ovary to the pelvic sidewall?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Suspensory ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Broad ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"In which region of the male reproductive system are most sperms stored?","answers":[{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":true},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"During the menstrual cycle, if fertilization occurs, which hormone is primarily responsible for maintaining the corpus luteum and preventing its degeneration?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadotropin releasing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"What is the role of the enzyme aromatase in the menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Initiating corpus luteum production","bool":false},{"option":"Converting androgens to estrogens","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitating ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Promoting FSH secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting progesterone production","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which hormone is responsible for the positive feedback loop leading to the surge in luteinizing hormone (LH) during ovulation?","answers":[{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"What is the primary function of the corpus luteum in the absence of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibiting estrogen production","bool":false},{"option":"Initiating menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Suppressing luteinizing hormone (LH) secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitating fertilization of the egg","bool":false},{"option":"Producing progesterone to maintain the uterine lining","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"In a laboratory, the hormone levels during different phases of the ovarian cycle of a 20-year-old female are monitored. During which of the following periods is the progesterone level the highest?","answers":[{"option":"Immediately before ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"During menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"During proliferative phase","bool":false},{"option":"At the end of menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Between ovulation and menstruation","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"What is the World Health Organization's (WHO) recommended age of initiation of weaning among normal-weight infants?","answers":[{"option":"After 1 year","bool":false},{"option":"9 months","bool":false},{"option":"3 months","bool":false},{"option":"6 months","bool":true},{"option":"1 year","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which one of the following is considered as the pillar of safe motherhood?","answers":[{"option":"Adolescent health","bool":false},{"option":"Nutritional care","bool":false},{"option":"Mental health","bool":false},{"option":"Women empowerment","bool":false},{"option":"Antenatal care","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female, para 3+1, with a history of gestational diabetes during her previous pregnancy, wants to have prolonged contraception as she does not want to conceive. Which method of family planning would be appropriate for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Intrauterine contraceptive devices (IUCD)","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal rings","bool":false},{"option":"Injectable progestin contraceptives","bool":false},{"option":"Condoms","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptives","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following methods of contraception inhibits ovulation?","answers":[{"option":"Barrier methods","bool":false},{"option":"Copper T device","bool":false},{"option":"Vasectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Hormonal contraceptives","bool":true},{"option":"Natural method","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 7-month pregnant lady visits an antenatal clinic for a regular checkup. Which vaccine must be recommended to this lady for safe delivery?","answers":[{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 20-year-old unmarried girl presents to the outpatient department with complaints of scanty menstrual flow and excessive facial hair growth. Her menstrual cycles are irregular and she bleeds every 2 to 3 months. Clinically, she is obese with a body mass index (BMI) of 30 kg/m². Thyroid is not palpable. Her lab tests show an altered FSH/LH ratio, normal TSH, and prolactin. Pelvic ultrasound shows peripherally arranged follicles with increased ovarian volume. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prolactinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS)","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroid nodule","bool":false},{"option":"Turner's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 13-year-old female patient is brought by her mother to the gynecology outpatient department with complaints of monthly lower abdominal pain for one year. She has not started menstruating but her secondary characteristics are normal. On examination, a bluish tense bulge is seen at the introitus. Which structural anomaly of the pelvis is suspected in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Mullerian obstruction","bool":true},{"option":"Renal anomalies","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylstilbestrol related anomalies","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian agenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian duplication","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 28-year-old female, married for 5 years, para 3+0, all pre-term deliveries at 32, 30, and 30 weeks, is found to have a developmental anomaly on a hysterosalpingogram. What is the most common developmental anomaly of the uterus responsible for recurrent preterm deliveries in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Complete septate uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Bicornuate uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Partial septate uterus","bool":false},{"option":"T-shaped uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic uterus","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the reason why prostatic hyperplasia predominantly affects muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cells do not proliferate","bool":false},{"option":"Overproduction of testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"5 alpha-reductase is located only in stromal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Dihydrotestosterone (DHT) is located only in the stromal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogenic effects","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male developed epididymitis. On culture, gram-negative diplococci, Neisseria gonorrhea, was located. Which one of the following laboratory culture media will be the most appropriate to grow this particular organism?","answers":[{"option":"Nutrient agar","bool":false},{"option":"Blood agar","bool":false},{"option":"Chocolate agar","bool":false},{"option":"Muller Hilton agar","bool":false},{"option":"Thayer-Martin agar","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Each year, there are an estimated 6 million new cases of syphilis globally in people aged 15-49 years. Which of the following best corresponds to the most common signs and symptoms of early or ''primary syphilis'' infection?","answers":[{"option":"Bullous pemphigoid infecting the limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Painful chancre, sores on the face","bool":false},{"option":"High grade fever with body aches","bool":false},{"option":"Painless chancre, sores on the genitals and/or mouth","bool":true},{"option":"Green vaginal discharge","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A healthy infant is born to a healthy mother; however, his weight decreases 5 to 10 percent within the first 2 to 3 days of his life. This may be due to which of the following reasons?","answers":[{"option":"Use of body proteins for energy","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of fluid from the body","bool":true},{"option":"Depletion of glycogen stores","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs get cleared of amniotic fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolism of brown fat for thermogenesis","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A medical college student constantly feels overwhelmed and stressed about upcoming exams. She often thinks, ''I am going to fail; I am not good enough.'' What cognitive behavior therapy (CBT) technique would be most appropriate for her?","answers":[{"option":"Behavior activation","bool":false},{"option":"Cognitive restructuring","bool":true},{"option":"Progressive muscle relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Free association","bool":false},{"option":"Aversive conditioning","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Mr. Xavier experiences a fear of public speaking, leading to avoidance of class presentations. Which cognitive behavior therapy (CBT) intervention would be most effective in addressing his fear?","answers":[{"option":"Exposure therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Progressive muscle relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Aversive conditioning","bool":false},{"option":"Behavior activation","bool":false},{"option":"Cognitive rehearsal","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 28-year-old sexually active woman comes to the clinic with a complaint of yellowish-greenish, foul-smelling vaginal discharge. She experiences pain during sexual intercourse and has red spots on her vaginal walls. She also mentions having discomfort and a burning sensation while urinating. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Donovanosis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Based on the data gathered by the World Health Organization (WHO), which sexually transmitted virus is recognized as a significant cause of cervical cancer, infecting thousands of individuals annually?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis B virus","bool":false},{"option":"HIV","bool":false},{"option":"Human papilloma virus (HPV)","bool":true},{"option":"Herpes simplex type 2","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following is related to the term ''chocolate cyst''?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus luteal cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Tubo-ovarian abscesses","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriotic cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Surface epithelial inclusion cyst","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Young athletes who abuse androgens should be made aware of the side effects of these drugs. Which one of the following is, however, not of concern?","answers":[{"option":"Increased muscle mass","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia due to bone marrow failure","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased spermatogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Overly aggressive behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Stunted growth","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A teenager seeks post-coital contraception. Which of the following preparations will be effective for this purpose?","answers":[{"option":"Ethinyl estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Norgestrel","bool":true},{"option":"Diethylstilbestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Clomiphene","bool":false},{"option":"Mifepristone","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"The process of PCR involves the amplification of DNA at high temperatures without the need to add fresh enzymes at each cycle. Which of the following enzymes is used in this process?","answers":[{"option":"Ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Taq polymerase","bool":true},{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Vent polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Primase","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"The estrogen levels are found to be very high just after the end of menstruation. What is the main function of estrogen at this time?","answers":[{"option":"Endometrium proliferation","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoclast production","bool":false},{"option":"Maturation of stromal cells of ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior pituitary gland stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Development of follicles","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Blotting techniques are used to identify various protein and nucleic acid sequences. What is the correct sequence of steps in any blotting technique?","answers":[{"option":"Blotting, hybridization, electrophoresis","bool":false},{"option":"Blotting, electrophoresis, hybridization","bool":false},{"option":"Electrophoresis, blotting, hybridization","bool":true},{"option":"Hybridization, blotting, electrophoresis","bool":false},{"option":"Electrophoresis, hybridization, blotting","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 33-year-old male develops urethritis having a characteristic fishy smell. On culture, the pathogen isolated is found to be Ureaplasma urealyticum. The characteristic fishy smell on this condition is due to the production of which of the following substances?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen sulfide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrogen dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Ammonia","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female with 32 weeks of gestational amenorrhea presents to the gynecology ward. Her ultrasound findings are placenta in the lower uterine segment covering the cervical os completely. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Abruptio placentae","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta previa","bool":true},{"option":"Placenta accreta","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta percreta","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta increta","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"In the DNA hybridization technique, a single-stranded DNA probe is allowed to interact with a complementary sequence in a sample. What is this specific type of hybridization known as?","answers":[{"option":"Western blotting","bool":false},{"option":"Southern blotting","bool":true},{"option":"Northern blotting","bool":false},{"option":"Southwestern hybridization","bool":false},{"option":"Fluorescence in situ hybridization","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 28-year-old man presents to the clinic with small, painless nodules in the genital region that have burst open creating beefy, red ulcers. The physician suspects it to be a case of Donovanosis. Which one of the following staining techniques will be used to diagnose the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Wright Giemsa stain","bool":false},{"option":"Gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Ziehl neelsen stain","bool":false},{"option":"India ink stain","bool":false},{"option":"Giemsa stain","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"What is the blotting technique used when RNA is the target molecule for hybridization and the detection involves the use of a labeled probe?","answers":[{"option":"Fluorescence in situ hybridization","bool":false},{"option":"Southern blotting","bool":false},{"option":"Southwestern blotting","bool":false},{"option":"Western blotting","bool":false},{"option":"Northern blotting","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"The initiation codon AUG that starts the translation process codes for which of the following amino acids?","answers":[{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Methionine","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following is the function of eIF-2-GTP during the eukaryotic translation process?","answers":[{"option":"Prevent ribosomal reassociation","bool":false},{"option":"To transport initiating amino acyl tRNA to P site","bool":true},{"option":"Guanine nucleotide exchange","bool":false},{"option":"Translocaton","bool":false},{"option":"Recognize stop codons","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"During translation, the ''non-traditional base pairing'' between the first nucleotide of the anticodon with the last nucleotide of the codon is most likely explained by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Shine-Dalgarno sequence","bool":false},{"option":"Wobble hypothesis","bool":true},{"option":"Central dogma","bool":false},{"option":"Charging of tRNA","bool":false},{"option":"Ubiquitination","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"While discussing a model of the pelvis, a student points out the levator ani muscle as one of the boundaries of the ischiorectal fossa. Which of the following correctly identifies the location of the levator ani muscle in relation to this fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Base","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following does not play any part in the formation of the gonadal ridge during the development of the reproductive system?","answers":[{"option":"Primordial germ cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Local mesenchyme (embryonic connective tissue)","bool":false},{"option":"Coelomic epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Ectodermal cells","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"Which of the following provides an important negative feedback mechanism for the control of spermatogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibin","bool":true},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadotropin releasing hormone (GnRH)","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"During capacitation, the permeability of the sperm membrane to which of the following ions increases significantly, altering the flagellum's activity and transforming it from a previously gentle undulating motion to a vigorous whip-like motion?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 38-year-old woman is concerned about the potential decline in fertility as she approaches menopause. Which hormonal changes are characteristic of the perimenopause period?","answers":[{"option":"Increased estrogen and progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced inhibin","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased estrogen only","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated FSH and LH","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2023","question":"A 32-year-old male presents to the reproductive endocrinology clinic with a complaint of not having children since he got married. The patient reports a lack of facial and body hair development, reduced muscle mass, and diminished libido. Upon further investigation, his plasma testosterone levels are found to be significantly low with low levels of follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH). Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Androgen insensitivity syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Primary testicular failure (hypergonadotropic hypogonadism)","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome (47, XXY)","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamic-pituitary dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Hypogonadotropic hypogonadism due to a genetic mutation","bool":true}]}]
export default arr